Desperate times call for. . .
Desperate Measures is a action, drama, thriller
film directed by Barbet Schroeder.
San Francisco police officer Frank Connor is in a frantic search for a
compatible bone marrow donor for his gravely ill son.
There's only one catch the potential donor is convicted multiple murderer Peter McCabe who sees a
trip to the hospital as the perfect opportunity to get what he wants most: freedom.
With McCabe's escape, the entire hospital becomes a battleground and Connor must pursue and,
ironically, protect the deadly fugitive who is his son's only hope for survival.
Peter McCabe, played by Michael Keaton.
Frank Conner, played by Andy Garcia.
Captain Jeremiah Cassidy, played by Brian Cox.
Dr. Samantha Hawkins, played by Marcia Gay Harden.
Nate Oliver, played by Erik King.
Vargas, played by Efrain Figueroa.
Desperate Measures is a 1998 American action thriller film starring Michael Keaton, Andy
García, Marcia Gay Harden and Brian Cox, directed by Barbet Schroeder.
It was filmed in both the San Francisco Bay Area and downtown Pittsburgh with such landmarks as
the BNY Mellon Center, the Allegheny County Courthouse and the Oakland Bay Bridge.
The film was released on January 30, 1998, and was
a critical and financial failure.
However, Andy García won an ALMA Award for "Outstanding
Actor in a Feature Film in a Crossover Role".
The film explores themes of chase, donation,
paranoia, terminal illness, leukemia.
The tone is intense and emotional and mind_bending.